美国佛罗里达州, 迈阿密
佛罗里达州南部地区地方法院
Is there any legal reason why sentence should not be pronounced?
本案有没有任何不能宣判的理由?
- No,your honour. - Yes,I've something to say.
- 没有, 法官先生 - 有! 我有话要说
You can put me away, but you can't put away...
你们可以把我关起来, 但是...
what's going to happen to you and to this whole country...
但是你们不能不顾你们和 这整个国家所面临的情况
Next time,we're going to...
下次, 我们要...
Do not say, that against you
别再说了, 这样对你不利
It is the judgement of this Court that the defendant,J. Huberman...
本庭宣判如下:被告J·休伯曼...
having found guilty of the crime of treason against the United States...
对美国犯有叛国罪
by the jury of this Court for the Southern District of Florida at Miami...
经效忠于总检察官的佛罗里达州迈阿密
be committed to the custody of the United States Attorney General...
南部地区法院陪审团审理
for imprisonment in an institution of the penitentiary type...
依法判处约翰休伯曼
for a period of 20 years.
有期徒刑20年
The defendant may be forthwith remanded to the custody of the U.S. Marshall.
该被告立即关押 交由执行法官予以监护
Court is now adjourned.
现在退庭
Here she comes!
她女儿来了
Just a minute,Miss Huberman! Look this way,would you,please?
请等等, 休伯曼小姐 拍个照吧, 休伯曼小姐
We'd like a statement from you, Miss Huberman,about your father.
休伯曼小姐, 关于你父亲,  我们想请你谈谈
Do you think your father got what he deserved?
譬如你父亲是否罪有应得?
Are you pleased your father's going to pay the penalty...
你对于你父亲作为德国情报人员
for being a German worker?
而判刑是否满意?
Let us know if she tries to leave town.
她要离开本市就报告我
Would you care to pause for some refreshments,Mr. Hopkins?
你歇一会, 吃点东西, 金斯先生
Alicia,were you really followed by a policeman?
艾丽茜娅, 真有警察盯着你们吗?
- It sounds exciting. - I'm going to shoot it out with him.
- 可真够劲 - 让我给他们点厉害尝尝
Had enough.
够了
Don't be silly. The important thing hasn't started yet.
噢, 得了, 说哪儿去了 咱们还没正经的喝呢
Everybody down here's got a stuffed fish hanging on the wall.
每个客人都喝了不少, 像墙上挂着鱼的标本
- Where do they get them? - Never seen the fish.
- 哪里? - 没看到鱼呀
How about you,handsome? Haven't I seen you somewhere before?
来一杯吗? 美男子 我以前见过你吗?
Oh,it doesn't matter. I like party-crashers.
噢, 没关系, 我欢迎不速之客
He's not a party crasher. I brought him.
他不是不速之客, 我带他来的
I wouldn't mind being followed by a cop.
我不介意有警察跟着我
I hate low,underhanded people like policemen pussy-footing after you.
我最恨那些下流警察在人后边死盯着
Of course,I'm a marked women,no?
也难怪, 我是被怀疑的人
I am liable to blow up the Panama Canal any minute now.
我可能随时去到那巴拿马运河
- You want some ice in it? - No,thank you.
- 要点冰吗? - 不, 谢谢
It's not becoming for a girl like you to be worried about cops.
你这么漂亮的姑娘为警察伤神太不该了
- You won't be tomorrow? - Oh,really?
- 明天就没事了 - 噢, 真的?
We sail at ten.
十点开船
Really? We just sail away?
真的, 就这么一走了之?
Show me a fish and I'll show you a liar.
你能找条鱼, 我就找到个说谎者
What this party needs is a little glam treatment.
我看这个地方都呆不住了
We'd better start breaking up. I have to be on board at nine.
早点散吧, 明天早上九点钟还要上船
One week in Havana and this whole thing will have blown over.
在哈瓦那呆一个星期 整件事就过去了
- Do you love me,Commodore? - You're a very beautiful woman.
- 你爱我吗? 船长 - 你非常美!
I'll have another drink to appreciate that.
喝一杯, 你这话我很欣赏
- Where are you going? - Fishing.
- 你去哪儿? - 钓鱼
This time of night? You're mad.
就这么晚去钓鱼?你发疯了
- How about you,still drinking? - There's no fish,day or night.
- 你怎么样, 还喝? - 不管白天还是晚上, 都没有鱼
You know something? I like you.
你知道吗?我喜欢你
- I'll see you on board at 9 o'clock. - I've to think that over.
- 明天九点钟船上见 - 让我...让我再想一想
You don't have to pack. We'll pick up some things in Havana.
你不用带行李, 我们在哈瓦那买好了
I think I'll have to leave him here to dry out,Alicia.
我看, 只能让他留在这醒醒酒, 艾丽茜娅
I'm sorry you have to go. It's been a perfectly hideous party.
很遗憾你们要走 这真是个非常完美的聚会
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
- 晚安 - 晚安
There's one more drink left.
剩下的还够每人一杯
- Shame about the ice. - What ice?
- 可冰不争气 - 什么?
- Gone. - What's gone?
- 没了 - 什么没了?
The ice.
冰块
Why do you like that song?
你干嘛喜欢这首歌?
It's a lot of hooey.
因为它表示离别
There's nothing like a love song to give you a good laugh.
世界上只有情歌让人高兴
That's right.
说得对
- It's stuffy in here,isn't it. - It might be.
- 屋里真闷啊 - 有一点
What about...
不如......
we have a picnic?
我们去野餐吧
Outside?
去外面?
Yeah,it's too stuffy in here for a picnic.
在屋里野餐, 多闷啊
- Want to finish that? - Shame to leave it.
- 你想干了它? - 剩下可惜呀
You're quite a boy.
真是孩子气
- My car is outside. - Naturally.
- 我的车在外边 - 当然
- Want to go for a ride? - Very much.
- 想兜兜风吗? - 想呀
What about your guests?
客人怎么办?
They'll crawl out under their own steam.
等他们缓过来自己会走的
I'm going to drive. That's understood.
说好了, 我来开车
- Don' you need a coat? - You'll do me.
- 不带件衣服? - 有你就行
Wait a minute.
等一等
Let me put this on you, you might catch cold.
把这个围上, 免得着凉
- How am I doing? - Not bad.
- 我开得怎么样? - 不坏
- Scared? - No.
- 你害怕了? - 不!
- You're not scared of anything... - Not too much.
- 当然了, 你什么都不怕 - 那也不是
- This fog gets me. - It's your hair in your eyes.
- 噢, 让雾迷住了 - 不, 是头发
What does the speedometer say?
车速...是多少?
Sixty-five.
65英里
I want to make it eighty and wipe that grin off your face.
我要开到80, 好让你笑不出来
I don't like gentlemen who grin at me.
我不喜欢男人 对我傻笑
A cop.
警察
What?
什么?
A policeman is chasing us. look.
后边有个警察在追我们 你瞧
They make me sick.
最讨厌这些警察
He wants to talk to you.
好像要跟你说话呢
Drunken driver.
酒后开车
A second offence. Now,I go to jail.
第二次违章, 要坐牢了
Whole family in jail! Who cares?
一家子都坐牢也好
Having a time for yourself, aren't you?
你倒是好自在啊!
People like you ought to be in bed.
你这号人该去睡党
- Drunk,huh? - Just a minute,officer.
- 醉了? - 等等, 先生
No arguments,mister: you ain't got a leg to stand on.
你别多嘴, 先生!  没什么借口可找的了
Sorry,but you didn't speak up.
对不起, 你怎么不早说?
That's all right.
没关系
- Sure you can handle it? - No trouble.
- 你治得了她? - 没问题
Well,you ought to know.
嗯, 你肯定知道怎么办
Where's the ticket?
罚单呢?
He didn't give me a ticket.
他没给我开罚单
- What's your name? - Devlin.
- 你叫什么? - 德弗林
You showed that cop something. He saluted you.
你把什么给警察看了 他给你敬礼了
- Did he? - I saw him.
- 是吗? - 我看见了
You double-crossing buzzard! You're a cop!
好啊!你这家伙 你也是警察!
We'll argue that later.
你抬举我了
- Get away from my car! - I'm going to take you home.
- 你给我滚下去, 你滚! - 我要送你回家
You're not going to take me home at all.
根本用不着你送
Move over!
移过来!
Come on!
来吧
Get out of my car,Federal cop! For crashing my party!
你给我滚下去, 闯到我家来的联邦警察!
Just like that buzzard with the glasses.
就像个蒙着脸的强盗
Give me alone. You're trailing me to get something out of me.
你给我走开!  你盯着我后头想坑我! 滚开!
You going to calm down?
安静点儿好吗?
Good, now move over.
好, 坐过去
I'll kill you, I'm not going to let...
放开你的手, 我不会让你...
You better drink that.
把它喝了吧
Why is this necessary?
为什么要这个?
Go on,drink it!
喝了它
Finish it!
都喝了
Feel better?
好点了吗?
What do you care how I feel?
你别管我好不好呢!
You,you cop...
你这警察!
What's this all about,huh?
这到底怎么回事?
- What's your angle? - What angle?
- 你打什么主意? - 什么主意?
- About last night. - Just wanted to be friends.
- 昨天晚上的事 - 我只想和你交个朋友
Friends, yes. So you could frame me, huh?
朋友? 你想害我!
No, got a job for you.
不, 给你找个事情干
Don't tell me, there's only...
得了吧, 你们...
There's only one job that you coppers would want me for.
你们警察找我只能为了一件事
- You can forget it, Mr... - Devlin.
- 噢, 算了, 你叫... - 德弗林
- What? - Devlin.
- 什么? - 德弗林
I'm no stool-pigeon, Mr. Devlin.
我可不是什么告密的, 德弗林先生
My department authorised me to engage you to do some work in Brazil.
局里派我聘请你 给我们做点事, 在巴西
Go away! The whole thing bores me!
滚开, 这种事让我讨厌
Some of the German gentry who were paying your father...
过去收买你父亲的一些德国人
are working in Rio.
正在里约热内卢活动
have you heard of IG Farben Enterprise?
听过IG法宾企业吗?
I tell you not interested
我说过没兴趣
Fabien has ambush in South America before the war
法宾是在战前就由南美埋伏在那
We're going to help the Brazilian government to smoke them out.
我们正和巴西政府合作把他们引出来
- My chief thinks that the daughter of... - Of a traitor?
我们的头认为你这样一个... - 奸细的女儿!
Well,he thinks you might be valuable in the work.
可能对这项工作很有用
They might sort of trust you.
他们会信任你
And you could make up a little for your daddy's peculiarities.
你可以在这方面为你的父亲作一些弥补
- Why should I? - Patriotism.
- 干嘛我该去呢? - 爱国主义!
That word gives me a pain. No,thank you.
提起这词我就头疼 不, 谢谢了
I don't go for patriotism or patriots.
什么爱国主义爱国者 我才不吃那一套呢
I could dispute that with you.
这一点可以辩论辩论
Waving the flag with one hand and picking pockets with the other's.
一只手挥舞国旗, 一只手扒人家的口袋
That's your patriotism.
这是你们的爱国主义吧
You can have it.
这一套你留着吧
We've had your bungalow wired for three months.
我们在你们家窃听了三个月
Conversation between John Huberman and daughter Alicia...
约翰休伯曼和他女儿的对话
6:00 p.m. January 9,1946, at Miami Beach,Florida.
l946年1月9日下午六时半 在佛罗里达州迈阿密
Some of the evidence that wasn't used at the trial.
审判中没有使用过的一些证据
- I don't want to hear that. - Relax,hard-boiled and listen.
- 我不要听 - 放松点儿, 好好听着
it's for both of us. There's a lot of money in it, Alicia.
这是给我们两个的, 有很多钱, 阿里茜娅
I told you before Christmas I wouldn't do it.
圣诞夜之前就告诉过你我不干
You can use your judgement. You can have anything you want.
好好想想吧, 你可以要什么有什么
- The work is easy. - I won't listen, father.
- 非常容易 - 我不想听, 爸爸
This is not your country, is it?
这不是你的国家, 对吧?
My mother was born here. We have American citizenship.
我妈妈生在这里, 我们是美国公民
Where's your judgement? In your feelings you're German.
你怎么这么看呢? 艾丽茜娅 在感情上你是德国人
You've got to listen to me. You don't know what we stand for.
该听我的, 你不知道我们为的是什么
I know what you stand for, you and your murdering swine.
我知道你们为的什么 你和你那些杀人的德国人
I've hated you ever since I found out.
我发现之后, 就恨透你们了
My daughter don't talk to me like that.
我的女儿不能这样跟我说话
- Don't ask me such a favour! - Alicia, keep your voice down.
- 你别到我屋里来! - 别那么大声
I hate you all.
我恨你们
I love this country. Do you understand? I love it.
我爱的是这个国家 你懂吗? 我爱它
I'll see you all hang before I raise a finger against it!
我宁愿看见你们全吊死, 也不会救你们
Now go on, get out of here. Or so help me, I'll turn you in.
现在快给我滚出去 天哪, 我要告你们
Don't ever come near me or speak to me about your rotten schemes.
别再到我跟前来谈你们肮脏的阴谋了
That doesn't prove much. I didn't turn him in.
这说明不了什么 我并没告
We didn't expect you to.
我们也没指望你告
Well, what do you say?
你想怎么样?
Go away and leave me alone!
走开, 别管我
I've my own life to lead!
我要过我自己的生活
Good times,that's what I want. And laughs,with people I like.
快快活活的 我要跟我喜欢的那些人在一起
And no underhanded cops who want to put me up in a shooting gallery...
我不要那些把我当活靶子打的卑鄙警察
but people of my own kind.
我要跟对我好的...
Who'll treat me right, and like me, and understand me.
喜欢我, 了解我的人在一起
Good morning, Alicia.
早上好, 艾丽茜娅
Oh, hello!
你好
Thought you might need a hand. We're sailing with the tide, you know.
我怕你今天早上要人帮忙 掌舵就开船了
- Are you ready? - Yes.
- 准备好了? - 是的
- Don't tell me you've forgotten. - Almost.
- 你没忘了这事吧? - 亲爱的 差一点
I'll help you pack, although you really don't need anything.
我来帮你收拾一下, 其实也用不着
- We've got everything on board. - Thank you,I'll pack myself.
- 船上什么都有 - 谢谢, 我自己来吧
We're moored at the hotel pier, you know the spot.
船停在马克旅馆前面, 你认识吗?
Yes.
认识
You're a darling, sweetest girl I ever knew.
真可爱, 你可真美
See you soon!
一会儿见
What about it? Plane leaves tomorrow morning early.
怎么样? 飞机明天一早就要起飞了
All right. You'd better tell him.
好吧 跟领头说吧
I'll tell her. See you later.
我跟她说吧 好, 一会儿见
That's a very nice looking man.
他长得很帅
You'll be seeing him in Rio.
到那儿你会常见他的
Oh no, no. I won't be seeing any men in Rio.
不, 在里约热内卢我谁都不见
Yes, you will. That's our boss,Paul Prescott.
要见的 他是我们的头保尔布来斯特
- Did he say anything about the job? - No.
- 他说要我干什么? - 没说
- No hints? - No.
- 没漏口风 - 没有
He had some news about your father he picked up at the last stop.
但他听到你父亲的一点消息
- What about him? - He died this morning.
- 什么消息? - 今天早上他死了
Oh!
哦!
- How? - Poison capsule.
- 怎么死的? - 服毒而死
- He did it himself? - Yes,in his cell.
- 自己服毒的? - 在监狱里
Sorry.
别难过
I don't know why I should feel so bad.
没想到我会这么难过
When he told me a few years ago what he was...
前几年, 他跟我说他是什么人时
everything went to pot, I didn't care what happened to me.
对于给我带来的影响, 我毫不在意
But now I remember how nice he was. How nice we both were.
现在想起, 他人还不错 我们俩过得挺好的
Very nice.
好极了
It's a very curious feeling.
我有一种很怪的感党
As if something had happened to me and not to him.
就好像出事的不是他, 是我!
You see, I don't have to hate him anymore.
现在我再也不用恨他了, 或者......
- Or myself. - We're coming into Rio.
- 恨我自己了 - 我们到了
Oh yes,we are.
是呀, 我们到了
I wonder if the embassy can get me a maid?
大使馆能不能给我找个女佣人
It's a nice apartment and I don't mind dusting and sweeping...
是一套很好的公寓, 打扫我不在乎
but I hate cooking.
就是讨厌做饭 我去问一下
-I ask - And while you're at it, find out when I go to work and what.
- 我去问一下 - 你去顺便问一下, 我什么时候工作, 什么工作
Yes,madam.
好的
- Care to have something else? - Have another drink?
- 先生, 你还要些什么? - 再喝一杯?
No, thank you, I've had enough.
谢谢, 我不喝了
I do. Whisky and soda.
我来一杯, 威士忌汽水
Well, do you hear that?
你听见了没有
I'm practically on the wagon. That's quite a change.
我基本是戒酒了, 是觉得不一样了
It's a phase.
装装样子
You don't think a woman can change?
你以为女人变不了?
- Sure, a change is fun. For a while. - For a while?
- 能变, 换个新鲜, 就一阵子 - 一阵?
What a rat you are, Devlin.
你真滑头, 德弗林
All right, you've been sober for eight days.
好了, 八天了, 你没醉过
And as far as I know you've made no new conquests.
据我所知, 你没找到新朋友
Well, that's something!
这算得了什么
Eight days, practically white-washed.
八天了! 简直白玉无暇
I'm very happy, Devlin.
可是我很快活
- Why don't you let me be happy? - Nobody's stopping you.
- 你干嘛不让我快活? - 没人拦着你
Why don't you give that copper's brain of yours a rest?
你为什么...不让你的警察脑瓜休息休息
Every time you look at me I can see it running over its slogans:
你每次瞧我, 我都觉得你在想:
Once a crook, always a crook. Once a tramp, always a tramp.
骗子永远是骗子, 妓女永远是妓女!
Go on, you can hold my hand. I won't blackmail you for it afterwards.
来呀, 握我的手呀 我不会为了这个而讹诈你
Scared?
害怕了?
I've always been scared of women. But I get over it.
我...一向有点怕女人 可现在不了
Now you're scared of yourself.
那你是怕你自己了
You're afraid you'll fall in love with me.
是怕你会爱上我?
That wouldn't be hard.
那可不难
Now, careful, careful.
噢, 当心点, 当心点!
You enjoy making fun of me, don't you.
你喜欢拿我开心是吗?
No, Devlin, I'm making fun of myself.
不, 德弗林, 我在拿我自己开心
I'm pretending I'm a nice unspoilt child...
我假装是个心中
whose heart is full of daisies and buttercups.
装满鲜花的天真浪漫的小姑娘
Nice daydream. Then what?
美好的梦, 以后呢?
I think I'll have another drink.
我还是再喝一杯
I thought you'd get around to it!
我料到你变不了
Make it a double!
来个双份
- Whisky and soda, double. - Yes,sir.
- 好吧, 咱们俩都来个双份 - 好的
Why won't you believe in me, Devlin?
你干嘛不信任我, 德弗林
Just a little.
哪怕一点点
Why won't you?
干嘛不信人?
I know why you won't, Dev: you're sore.
我知道你为什么不信人
You're sore because you've fallen for a little drunk you tailed in Miami.
那是因为你在迈阿密逼我的时候 你火了 看到我有点醉了
And you don't like it, it makes you sick all over, doesn't it?
你不喜欢这个 打心眼里不喜欢这个
People will laugh at you. The invincible Devlin in love...
怕人家会笑话你这个情场老手...
with someone who isn't worth even wasting the words on.
居然会爱上一个不值一提的女人
Poor Devlin, in love with a no-good gal. It must be awful, I'm sorry.
可怜的德弗林 爱上这么个女人有多糟
I assure you she's the perfect type for the job.
各位, 我肯定, 艾丽茜娅是能胜任的
It's not the girl, it's this German scientist I'm worried about.
我担心的不是她 那个德国科学家
I simply question why we don't find some way of taking them into custody.
我倒想问问 为什么我们不把他们这些人抓起来?
It' do no good,even if we arrested their leader,Alex Sebastian...
那没用 就是把塞巴斯蒂安抓起来
tomorrow another foreign man takes his place and the work goes on.
他很快就派另外一个人去代替他的位置
Yes, you're right.
说的对
I see,Captain Prescott, your method is the best way.
保尔布莱斯特上校, 我看还是你的办法好
Well, she's good at making friends with gentlemen...
是呀, 她擅长跟男人交际啊
and we want somebody inside his house in his confidence.
而我们想派个人打进去取得对方信任
- You've faith in this procedure? - Yes, with somebody on the side...
- 你对这个行动是否有把握? - 有, 只要能派个人...
- Have you consulted the young lady? - No, not yet.
- 你跟那小姐商量过吗? - 不, 还没有
Our man Devlin just brought her down here the other day.
事实上, 我手下的德弗林前不久 刚把她带到这儿来
Now we're waiting for Sebastian to come back to Rio.
正在等待塞巴斯蒂安回来
Has your man Devlin told her the nature of the work?
德弗林跟那位小姐谈过工作性质吗?
No, we haven't discussed it with him at all.
还没有, 我们还没有服德弗林谈呢
I can set your mind at rest about her.
那个女的你们尽管放心
You're sure of her political side?
政治方面可靠吗?
Oh, yes.
可靠
Well, there is nothing to be lost if we proceed as you advise.
那么, 照你的办法进行吧 看上去我们是万无一失的
That's fine. I'll give Devlin his instructions right away.
那好吧, 我马上就给德弗林指示
it's nice out here!
这儿多好啊!
Let's not go out for dinner. Let's stay here.
别出去吃了, 就在这儿
We have to eat.
那就做点吃的
We can eat here. I'll cook.
就在这儿吃 我做饭
I thought you didn't like to cook.
你不是不爱做饭的吗?
No, I don't like to cook.
我不爱做饭
But I have a chicken in the ice-box and you're eating it.
冰箱里有只鸡, 我们烤来吃
What about all the washing up afterwards?
吃完了还得洗半天
We'll eat it with our fingers.
我们就用手吃
Don't we need any plates?
连盘子也不用?
Yes, one for you and one for me.
用, 你一个, 我一个
Do you mind if have dinner with you tonight?
那我就留下吃饭吧
I'd be delighted.
你赏光了
- Where are you going? - If we're going to stay in...
- 你去哪儿? - 如果我们决定在这
I've to telephone the hotel to see if there are any messages.
先打个电话问问旅馆有没有人给我留话
- You have to? - I have to.
- 非得打吗? - 非得打
- This is a very strange love affair. - Why?
- 这种爱情太古怪了 - 为什么?
Maybe the fact that you don't love me.
因为实际上你并不爱我
Hello?
喂
Paris Hotel?
皇宫旅馆?
Reception desk?
你是卡米代?
This is T.R. Devlin. Are there any messages for me?
我是德弗林 有人给我留话吗?
I don't love you. How do you know?
要是不爱你, 我会说的
You haven't said anything.
你等于没说
Actions speak louder than words.
行动比空话强
There is? Good, read it to me, please.
有呀 好, 念给我听吧
Thanks.
谢谢
Prescott wants me over right away.
保尔布来斯特要我马上去
- Did he say what about? - No.
- 他说什么事了? - 没说
- Maybe it's our assignment. - Probably.
- 是谈我们的工作? - 有可能
Do you want me to bring anything back?
要我带点什么东西回来吗?
Yes, what about a nice bottle of wine to celebrate?
好啊, 带瓶好酒回来, 庆祝一下
What time shall I come back?
那我几点回来?
Seven o'clock.
七点
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
- 再见 - 再见
- What is it, Devlin, what's the matter? - I don't know if she'll do it.
- 怎么了?德弗林, 你这是怎么了? - 不知道她干不干
What do you mean? You haven't discussed it with her, have you?
你怎么知道她不肯干 你没有跟她谈过吗?
No, I didn't know what the job was until this moment.
没有, 我现在才知道让她干什么
- What do you mean she wouldn't do it? - She's not that type of woman.
- 那你怎么知道她不肯干呢? - 我猜她不是那种女人
I don't understand your attitude.
我不明白你的态度
- Why do you think she won't do it? - Well, she's had no experience.
- 为什么你以为她不肯干 - 她没有这种经验
Come on, what experience does she lack, do you think?
得了, 依你看, 她还缺少什么经验
She's never been trained for that... They'll see through her.
她没受过训练, 会被人家识破的
Alicia Huberman was chosen...
我们不仅是因为她父亲的背景
not only because her father gives her an ideal background...
而且还因为塞巴斯蒂安跟她很熟
but because Sebastian knows her.
所以才挑选她
Yes.
对了
He was once in love with her.
塞巴斯蒂安还爱过她
Oh, I didn't know that.
哦, 这我倒不知道
I don't know why we're arguing about petty things like this.
我不知道为什么要争论这样的小事
We've got important work to do.
我们有重要工作要做
Sebastian's house is a cover-up. whatever Fabien group up to here.
塞巴斯蒂安家是个神秘地方 不管法宾集团在这干些什么
- We've got to get Miss Huberman inside and find out
- 我们得把休伯曼小姐派进去
what's going on there. - yeah that's right
看看里面搞什么鬼 - 对
I' think you'd better go back to Miss Huberman and explain it to her.
我看你还是回去跟 休伯曼小姐讲一讲要她干些什么
- I... - What is it?
- 我... - 怎么了?
Nothing, sir.
没什么
I thought you were going to say something.
噢, 你好像要说什么!
How is the meeting to be arranged?
怎么让他们俩见面
We've discussed that. The riding club would be the best place.
我们讨论过了 我看那个骑马俱乐部最合适了
Sebastian usually rides there in the mornings.
塞巴斯蒂安早上经常在那里骑马
The rest is up to you and Miss Huberman.
德弗林, 你和休伯曼小姐看着办吧
- Okay, Devlin, that's all. - All right.
- 好, 德弗林, 就这些 - 好吧
- Dev, is that you? - Huh?
- 德弗林, 是你吗? -嗯
I'm glad you're late.
幸亏你来晚了
This chicken took longer than I expected.
没想到这鸡烤这么久
What did they say?
他们怎么说?
I hope it isn't done too much. It caught fire once.
这鸡恐怕烤过头了 还差点烤糊了
I think it's better if I cut it up out here.
我看我还是先尝一尝
Unless you want a half of one for yourself.
你要是不想用手撕着吃
We're going to have knives and forks after all.
那我看还是一本正经的吃一顿
I've decided we're going to eat in style.
我已经把刀叉摆好了
Marriage must be wonderful with this sort of thing going on everyday.
结婚一定挺有意思的, 每天都要忙乎这些事
I wonder if it's too cold out here.
外边是不是太凉了?
Maybe we should eat inside.
进去吧
Hasn't something like this happened before?
像这样, 你过去有过吗?
What's the matter?
怎么回事?
Don't look so tense. Troubles?
别绷着脸, 出事了?
Well, I think you'd better tell Mamma what's going on.
美男子, 跟妈妈说怎么回事?
All this secrecy's going to ruin my little dinner.
这样呆着连吃一顿吃都吃不好
Come on, Mr. D., what is darkening your brow?
好了, 先生, 干嘛愁眉苦脸的
- After dinner. - No, now.
- 吃完了再说 - 不, 说
I'll make it easy for you.
你就别为难了
The time has come when you must tell me...
是不是到了你该告诉我
you have a wife and two adorable children.
你家里有老婆孩子的时候了?
And this madness between us can't go on any longer.
我们只不过是一时冲动, 瞎胡闹
I bet you've heard that line often enough.
这种话你常听说?
Right below the belt every time.
你老是对我这样
That isn't fair, Dev.
太不公平了
Skip it.
不谈这个
We've other things to talk about. We've got a job.
我们还有别的事要谈, 你有个任务
Oh, so, there's a job.
到底有任务了
You remember a man named Sebastian?
你...认识一个叫塞巴斯蒂安的吗?
- Alex Sebastian? - Yes.
- 亚历克塞巴斯蒂安? -是的
One of my father's friends, yes.
是我父亲的一个朋友
He had quite a crush on you.
他过去爱过你
I wasn't very responsive.
我对他不怎么样
He's here at the head of a large German business concern.
他现在在这儿, 是个德国大公司的头
- His family always had money. - He's part of the combine that...
- 他们家族一向很有钱 - 过去德国战争机器有他一份
built up the German war machine and wants to keep it going.
现在还想东山再起
- Something big? - It has all the earmarks of being it!
- 这事可不小啊 - 这事是不小
We've to contact him.
我们要和他接触
Go on, let's have all of it.
好, 把话都说了吧
We're meeting him tomorrow. The rest is up to you.
明天跟他见面 以后就看你的了
You've got to work on him and land him.
你要下功夫笼住他 当你的间谍
Mata Hari! She makes love for papers.
为偷文件, 牺牲色相
There are no papers.
不要偷文件
You'll land him, Find out what's going on inside his house...
只要笼住他 看看他们家里到底搞的什么鬼
what the group around him is up to and report to us.
他周围的人打的什么主意 报告给我们
I suppose you knew about this pretty little job of mine all the time.
我看我这个好差事你大概早就知道的了
No, I only just found out about it.
不 我也是刚刚知道的
Well, did you say anything?
你什么也没说?
I mean, that maybe I wasn't the girl for such shenanigans?
我是说... 也许我这个人干这种活不合适
I figured that was up to you. If you'd care to back out...
这由你自己决定吧 你要想不干的话
I suppose you told them Alicia Huberman...
你总说过休伯曼小姐用不了多久
will have this Sebastian eating out of her hand in a couple of weeks.
就能叫塞巴斯蒂安乖乖的听她的
She's good at that, always was.
这她在行
I didn't say anything.
我什么也没说
Not a word for that little love-sick lady you left an hour ago.
你真的没有? 替刚分手的心爱的人说句话
I told you that's the assignment.
我跟你说了, 这是公事
Well now, don't get sore, Dev.
好了, 别费口舌了
I'm only fishing for a little bird-call from my dream man.
我真是想... 让我心爱的人能为我再说两句
One little remark such as:
就像这样的话:
How dare you gentlemen suggest that Alicia Huberman...
"怎么可以, 先生们" "让艾丽茜娅休伯曼..."
the new Miss Huberman,  be submitted to so ugly a fate?
"那个改邪归正的休伯曼小姐..." "...遭到如此丑恶的命运"
That's not funny.
一点也不滑稽
- Do you want me to take the job? - You're answering for yourself.
- 你让我干点什么? - 你自己说吧
- I'm asking you. - It's up to you.
- 我是问你 - 你决定
Not a peep.
这么难吗?
Darling, what you didn't tell them,  tell me.
你没跟别人说的就跟我说了
That you believe I'm nice, that I love you and I'll never change back.
说你相信我是真心爱你 永远不会变心
I'm waiting for your answer.
我在等你回答
What a little pal you are.
哼, 你可真够朋友
Never believing me, huh?
还是不相信我!
Not a word of faith.
一点也不相信!
Just down the drain with Alicia,  that's where she belongs.
让艾丽茜娅见鬼去吧 她活该的
Oh, Dev, Dev!
噢, 德弗林
When do I go to work for Uncle Sam?
我什么时候为山姆大叔效劳
Tomorrow morning.
明天早晨
We shouldn't have had this out here. It's all cold now.
噢, 真不应该把鸡搁在这儿 给吹凉了
What are you looking for?
你在找什么?
I had a bottle of champagne. I must have left it somewhere.
买了瓶酒, 忘了搁在哪儿了
In case you're asked,  I'm with Pan American Airways.
有人问我就说是泛美航空公司的
- As Devlin? - Yes, Public Relations Officer.
- 叫德弗林? - 管对外联络的
Anything else?
还有什么?
No, except we met on the plane coming in from Miami.
我们是来的时候在飞机上认识的
The less detail the better.
说的越少越好
- Are you sure that's him? - Yes.
- 肯定是他? - 对!
We'll go by him easy and let him spot you. Come on.
过去, 让他认出你
I guess I'm the girl nobody remembers.
我看没人会记得我的
- Was it Sebastian? - Yes.
- 是塞巴斯蒂安吗? - 是的
We'll stick around: give him another chance.
我们在这儿转一会, 再给他一个机会
My dear Alicia,  will you forgive me for being late?
亲爱的艾丽茜娅, 对不起, 我来晚了
Last minute conference at the office. You got my message?
公司临时召开会议, 接到电话吗?
- Yes, it's all right, Alex. - It was sweet of you to wait.
- 没关系, 亚历克斯 - 让你久等了
- I was afraid you might run off. - Oh, I'm not that easily put off.
- 还以为你走了 - 你想甩也甩不掉我
I was too anxious to meet you again.
我总惦着跟你见面
You know, I'm tired.
我真有点累了
The worst thing about business is it makes you feel old and look old.
做买卖总是让人容易老, 像个老头似的
You seem to have escaped all of that.
为何你一点都不像
Four years of dullness and disintegration.
四年来的奔波劳碌
Awful!
太可怕了
Alex, you look younger than you did in Washington.
你比在华盛顿时年轻多了
It's a temporary improvement,  entirely due to your presence.
这是临时的变化 完全是由于你在这儿
You always affected me like a tonic.
我一看见你就精神振奋
But perhaps now with you here in Rio...
你大概要在这里住一阵子吧
unless you insist on running away from me again...
除非你在存心躲着我
- Oh, would you like another drink? - Yes, thank you.
- 你要再喝一杯? - 好的, 谢谢
Two martinis.
两杯马爹利!
Do you know him?
认识他?
No, I don't think so,  but he seems familiar.
不, 不认识 可是有点面熟
Captain Prescott,  intelligence man.
保尔普来斯克特上校, 搞情报的
He's down here as part of the Washington espionage.
他在这里是替华盛顿搞间谍活动
The American Embassy's loaded with them.
美国大使馆尽是这号人
Really?
是吗?
He's really handsome, isn't he?
他挺漂亮, 不是吗?
I'm allergic to American agents.
看见特务人员我就反感
Their fine points don't particularly appeal to me.
他们的优点并不十分吸引我
They've bothered you since you came down?
你一来他们就来找你的麻烦了?
No, no, not yet.
没有, 还没有
They were troublesome in Miami?
在迈阿密他们找你麻烦了?
Yes, that's why I left right after the trial:
所以一判决我就走了
to get away from their snooping.
省得他们探头探脑的
I wondered why you left your father.
到底为什么离开你父亲?
He insisted. He was so unselfish.
是他坚持的
He kept worrying about me and begging me to leave.
他不顾自己老惦着我 一定要我离开
I had no idea he was going to die.
我完全没想到他会死的
Many things have died for all of us. We mustn't let our spirit die with them.
为了我们很多事物死亡了 我们的精神不能死
Perhaps I can help you to forget. I'd like to.
我很愿意帮你忙的, 忘记那些悲痛!
Well, it's odd...
真怪
but I feel at home with you.
和你一起就无拘无束
You know, my dear...
你知道吗?
I knew this was going to happen.
我知道会这样的
I knew when we met the other day...
我们见面那天我就知道
that if I... saw you again...
我再见到你
I'd feel what I used to for you.
会像从前一样
The same hunger.
一样的爱你
You're so lovely, my dear.
亲爱的, 你是那么可爱
Now I'm going to make a fool of myself again.
现在我不会再做傻瓜了
There's someone else, of course. Who is it this time?
当然, 一定有人了, 这人是谁?
That Mr Devlin you were with?
跟你一起的德弗林先生
There is no-one.
谁呀?
He seemed attentive.
他好像对你很殷勤
Mr. Devlin has pestered me with his attentiveness ever since I arrived...
我到这儿以后 德弗林先生就死盯着我献殷勤
I met him on the plane from Miami.
我们是在飞机上认识的
You made a pretty couple.
挺像一对的!
Oh, Alex! Mr. Devlin doesn't interest me.
得了, 亚历克斯 德弗林才不在我眼里
I was so Ionely that day...
那天太无聊
I could have gone riding with Peter Rabbit.
才找个人去骑马
You'll let me help your Ioneliness?
想让我帮你忘记孤独吗?
You're very sweet to forget what a brat I was once.
你真好, 你居然不计较 我过去那样...调皮
My dear, I shall test out your repentance.
亲爱的, 你对我的交情一下就能...试出来
At once.
立刻
Will you have dinner with me again tomorrow night?
跟我一起吃饭, 好吗?
- Thank you very much. - My house?
- 谢谢你 - 在我家!
Yes, how nice.
那太好了
My mother's giving a dinner party.
我母亲明天晚上请客
- She won't mind an extra guest? - An old friend is never an extra guest.
- 多一个客人他不介意吗? - 她永远都不会嫌多的
- Well, shall we order now? - Yes, yes, I'm starved.
- 好, 我们该点菜了 - 我真饿坏了 是吗?
Let's see, what shall we have for our first dinner together?
来, 看看我们... 我们第一次吃晚饭吃点什么
- Good evening. - Very good.
- 你们好 - 很好
Yes, yes, isn't it?
真漂亮 这...还可以吧
I'd like you to wear these. They're rented for the occasion.
你把这个戴上, 是特地租来的
- Would you help me please, I can't... - What? Yes, certainly.
- 谢谢你帮我... - 当然可以
Thank you.
谢谢
- So, the old boy knew me, eh? - He thought you were very handsome.
- 那家伙还认识我? - 他还觉得你很漂亮
Well, you don't say. Sorry, I'm not going with you.
真有这事 我不送你去了
Oh, Dev will pick those up later.
用完了交给德弗林
Try to memorise the names of all the people you see there tonight.
记住你今晚见到的所有人的名字
The men, I mean.
是男的
And get their nationalities. That's very important.
还有他们的国籍, 这点很重要
You mean the Germans? That won't be difficult for me.
要是德国人, 我听得出口音
I suggest you don't ask any questions. Just use your eyes and ears.
我建议你不要多问 你要多听, 多看
They're a keen and desperate bunch. Don't underestimate them.
这帮亡命徒很精明, 别小看他们
Thanks for your instructions. Good evening.
谢谢你的指示
By the way, unless you have something very urgent to report...
还有一件事 除非有非常紧急的情况要报告
I suggest you two keep shy of each other for the next few days.
我们建议你们最近几天不要见面
Just in case Sebastian's people want to check on you after your visit.
这是怕你去了以后, 他们会调查你
- I understand. - Good luck.
- 我懂了 - 就这些了, 祝你成功!
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
- 再见! - 再见!
Good evening. I'm Miss Huberman,  would you tell Mr. Sebastian I'm here?
晚上好, 我是休伯曼小姐 请通知塞巴斯蒂安先生
- Miss Huberman? - Yes.
- 休伯曼小姐? -是的
Please forgive me for keeping you waiting.
请你原谅, 让你久等了
Not at all.
没关系
You resemble your father very much. I'm Alex's mother.
你很像你父亲 我是亚历克的母亲
I knew when I saw you.
一见就认出来了
Alex has always admired you. Now, at last, I know why.
亚历克很崇拜你, 现在我知道为什么了
You're very kind.
你客气了
We thought unusual that you did not testify at your father's trial.
你父亲受审的时候你没作证 他不寻常啊
He didn't want me to.
他不要我作证
He refused to let his lawyers call me on the stand.
他不让律师出来让我作证
I wonder why?
到底为什么?
Hello! Alicia!
你好, 艾丽茜娅
I'm so glad!
我真高兴
- You met my mother. - Yes, we just met.
- 认识我妈了吗? - 我们刚认识
You didn't meet Alicia when we were in Washington, did you mother?
四年前你没在华盛顿见到艾丽茜娅
- I don't know where you were then? - I think we should join our guests.
- 当时我不知道你在哪儿 - 亚历克斯, 我们去看看别的客人
- May I take your robe? - Thank you.
- 把披肩给我 - 谢谢
Miss Huberman, may I present Eric Mathis?
休伯曼小姐, 我来介绍一下 埃瑞克·马迪斯!
- How do you do? - How do you do?
- 你好 - 你好!
William Rothman.
威廉姆·罗斯曼先生
How do you do?
你好!
Very honoured.
很荣幸!
Emil Hupka.
伊米尔·虎泊克先生
How do you do?
你好!
Delighted.
很愉快!
And Mr. Nair.
诺夫先生
And Dr. Anderson.
安德森博士
Dr. Anderson.
it gives me great pleasure.
见到你真高兴
Dr. Anderson is our Guest of Honour tonight.
今天晚上安德森博士是主客
You mustn't bore Miss Huberman with discourses on science.
亚历克斯, 你不要谈科学 会让休伯曼小姐厌烦
Not before dinner, anyway.
最少不要在饭前谈
Dinner is served, Madame.
入席了, 夫人
Dr. Anderson, you will sit beside me, over there.
安德森博士, 你在那边, 坐在我的旁边
Eric, you will sit next to Miss Huberman.
亚历克斯, 你坐在休伯曼小姐的旁边
You have just come from Spain, Senora?
夫人, 你是刚从西班牙来的吗?
A few weeks ago. It seems ages.
几个星期以前, 就好像很久
Travel does not mean anything anymore, it goes so swiftly.
现在的旅行就是快捷
One has the feeling of not going anywhere.
去哪儿都那么方便
I suppose we can expect the rocket ships...
我猜想我们今后可以
to be carrying us across the oceans very soon.
坐更快的火箭跨过大洋
We can expect many strange things.
你总有奇思妙想
- Did you see a good movie, Eric? - No, I was disappointed.
- 下午的电影好吗? - 不, 太失望了
It must have been a comedy. Eric loves to go to the movies to cry.
一定是个喜剧 艾瑞克就爱到电影院哭鼻子
He's very sentimental.
他心肠很软
I'm afraid, gentlemen, that something must be done about Emil.
我看对伊米尔得想想办法了
I don't know.
怎么说呢
It was an understandable slip: the man was tired.
这是个不应该的疏忽 他过于疲劳了
No, it's a very dangerous slip.
这是个很危险的疏忽
It's not the first one. There have been several other lapses.
这可不是第一次 已经试过好几次了
There'll be more, if we permit it.
要是不管, 还会这样
That's bad, that's very bad!
这不好, 很不好
I think, gentlemen, you can leave it to me to find some way.
我看诸位, 把这事交给我吧
When you drive up to Metropolis,  the road winds quite a bit.
我有办法, 往山顶去的那条路弯弯曲曲
It is very high. There are some very awkward turns.
山也很高 而且有很多急转弯
I'm sure I'll not have any difficulty...
我要搭伊米尔的车
in getting Emil to give me a lift in his car.
...没什么困难
It's quite a trick to jump clear.
但是要跳车, 就不那么简单了
I'll just have to be careful,  that is all.
我加点小心就是了
Turned my ankle the last time.
刚才的事不会再发生了
Madame says will you join the others or will you take your coffee in here?
夫人问, 你们是跟客人一起喝咖啡 还是在这喝呢?
I think we'll take coffee in here,  Emil.
我们就在这儿喝
I'm very sorry gentlemen,  to make such an exhibition.
很抱歉, 这样当众出丑
Oh, nonsense!
没别的事
We all have nerves!
你有点紧张了
You've been overworking.
你太累了
Don't you think so, Rothman?
你看对不对?
You need a rest.
你需要休息
Your health is very important to us.
健康非常重要
That's very considerate. I am very tired.
你想的真周到, 我是很疲劳了
Now, I think perhaps if you'll make my pardon to the ladies, Alex...
所以, 现在... 我看也许... 你替我跟那些女人们告辞, 亚历克斯
for my leaving so early, then I go...
我没能奉陪, 很抱歉
I think maybe, Emil, it would be better if I came with you.
伊尔米, 还是我和你一起去的好
If you try to drive yourself all the way up to Metropolis...
刚吃完了饭, 又是这么远的路
it might be too much for you.
一个人开车会受不了的
I shall drive you.
我来给你开车
No!
不!
It'd be too much for you all that way. That's too much to ask.
这么远的路你恐怕也受不了 怎么可能你驾...
Nonsense, I'd love to go!
哪儿的话, 我愿意去
Come on, Emil.
走吧, 伊米尔
Goodnight, gentlemen.
再见, 诸位
Goodnight, Alex.
再见, 亚历克斯
I hope you feel better in the morning, Emil.
明天你就会恢复疲劳了, 伊米尔
Thank you, and I'm very sorry to make a scene before strangers.
谢谢, 我真是抱歉当着外人出了这样的丑
Very sorry.
十分抱歉
Thank you, Alex, for an excellent dinner.
谢谢你这顿丰富的晚餐
And please tell your mother from me that the desert was superb.
告诉你母亲, 特别是那道点心太好了
Miss Huberman has been gone a long time.
休伯曼小姐去了好半天了
Is it necessary for you to address Alicia as Miss Huberman?
为什么老是叫艾丽茜娅做休伯曼小姐呢?
I do wish you'd be a little more cordial to her.
我希望你不要对她太见外了
Really? I thought I was behaving very well.
是吗?我觉得我对她很不错了
Has she been complaining about me?
她对我有点抱怨吗?
- No, no. - I'm grateful.
-没有 - 感激之至
You might smile at her.
你要对她随和些
Wouldn't it be a little too much if we both grinned at her like idiots?
要是我们俩都像客人 一样对待她那不太过份吗?
Please, mother,  I want to enjoy myself.
好了, 妈妈, 让我好好看看
Is it so boring to sit with me alone?
跟我在一起有那么烦啊
Not at all, not at all.
一点也不!
- Hello! - Hello!
- 你好! - 噢, 你好!
- I thought I saw you. - How are you?
- 我想我看见你了 - 你好吗?
Fine thanks. Great turn out, isn't it?
好, 谢谢 人可真不少
Yes.
是啊!
- Where are they? - In a box in the stand.
- 他们在哪儿? - 在看台包厢里
I don't think they can see us,  Alex and his mother.
他们母子俩不会看见我们
Don't telephone me any more. Just rely on my popping up.
别再打电话给我 下次我来找你
- Can you hear me? - Sure, go ahead.
- 听得清吗? - 你说吧!
- Have you heard of Dr. Anderson? - No.
- 听说过安德森博士吗? - 没有
He's some kind of a scientist: kind face, sixty years old, grey hair.
好像是个科学家 人挺和气, 头发银灰色
Deep crease in the forehead.
前额皱纹很深
- Tall or short? - Short.
- 身材呢? - 矮小
- Emil Hupka, heard of him? - No.
- 伊尔米·虎泊克听说过? - 没有
He made quite a scene about a wine bottle the other night.
那天晚上, 他为了一瓶酒紧张了好一阵
Didn't like the vintage?
是瓶陈酒?
He seemed to think there was something else in the bottle.
好像那瓶里不是酒
- Was there? - No, it was wine. We drank it.
- 那是什么? - 是酒, 我们都喝了
- Has he pulled anything since? - Haven't seen him since.
- 后来, 他又干了什么? - 后来他就不见了
Anything else?
还有什么?
Nothing important.
没什么发现了
Just a minor item, but you may want it for the record.
只不过是一些供你参考的消息
What is it?
是什么?
You can add Sebastian's name to my list of playmates.
跟我逢场作戏的人 当中加上塞巴斯蒂安的名字
Pretty fast work.
你干得不赖
- That's what you wanted, wasn't it? - Skip it.
- 那不正是你要的吗? - 行了
- Are you betting on this race? - No.
- 你下注了吗? - 没有
Alex says number ten is sure to win. He knows the owner.
10号领先, 看来塞巴斯蒂安眼力不错
Thanks for the tip.
多谢你的指点
He says they've been holding him back all season...
亚历克斯说他们整个赛季运气都不错
I can't help recalling some of your remarks about being a new woman.
不要跟我说这些 你是他的新女友
Daisies and buttercups, wasn't it?
他是你的情人和保镖
Oh, you idiot! What are you sore about?
白痴, 你就只会说这些伤心话?
- You knew very well what I was doing. - Did I?
- 知道我在干什么就好 - 是吗?
You could have stopped me with one word, but you threw me at him.
你一句话就能阻止我 没有, 你没有, 你把我扔给他
I threw you at nobody.
我没有这么做
Didn't you tell me to go ahead?
不都是你告诉我的吗?
A man doesn't tell a woman what to do. She tells herself.
男人不能告诉女人去做什么, 除了她自己
I almost believed in that little hokey-pokey miracle of yours...
你的小把戏差点让我相信女人...
that a woman like you could ever change her spots.
可以为她喜欢的人作出牺牲
Oh, you're rotten!
你胡说
That's why I didn't try to stop you. The answer had to come from you.
我之所以没阻止你, 答案在你自己
- I see, some kind of love test. - That's right.
- 我懂了, 你想试探我 - 没错
You never believed in me anyway...
你从来就没相信过我的感情
Lucky for both of us I didn't. It'd have been pretty if I'd believed.
注定我是不幸的 不然连你也一样
If I'd figure: she'll never be able to go through with this.
我认为她从来就没有恒心
She can make it over by love.
她一定会移情别恋
If you only once had said that you loved me.
要是你曾说过你爱我
You chalked up another boyfriend that's all, no harm done.
听着, 你得到你的新男友, 不会有什么伤害
I hate you!
我恨你
There's no occasion to. You're doing a good work.
别再说了, 你干得很出色
Number ten's out in front.
十号马跑在前面
Looks as if Sebastian knows how to pick them.
看来亚历克斯非常老道
Is that all you have to say to me?
你就只想跟我说这些吗?
Dry your eyes, baby,  it's out of character.
把眼相擦干净, 不合身份
Except keep on your toes. It's a tough job we're on.
振作起来, 要干的事多着呢
Snap out of it, here comes dreamboat.
别哭了, 你的心上人来了
Hello, Alex! It was so exciting, a beautiful horse.
噢, 亚历克斯!赛马真紧张, 多好的马
- Do you remember Mr. Devlin, Alex? - How do you do?
- 德弗林先生!  - 你好!
Hello, Alicia tells me you had a bet on number ten.
艾丽茜娅叫我买10号马票
Sorry I didn't get the tip earlier. So long.
可是知道晚了!
See you sometime, Dev.
再见 再见, 德弗林
It was a wonderful race. Did you have much money on the winner?
这场赛马太好了, 你赢了多少?
I didn't see the race,
我没看赛马 没有?
I thought I saw you looking through your field glasses.
好像看见你用望远镜在看
I was watching you and your friend, Mr. Devlin.
我在看你和你的朋友德弗林先生
I suppose that's why you left my mother and me.
我看这就是你离开我的原因
- You both had an appointment... - Don't be absurd!
- 你跟他有个约会 - 想哪儿去了
I met him purely by accident.
我们是偶然碰上的
You didn't seem very anxious to get away from him.
你好像舍不得跟他分手
- Oh, he's just... - I watched you.
- 噢, 他只是... - 我都看见了
I thought maybe you were in love with him.
我看你是爱上了他
Don't talk like that. I detest him.
别这么说, 我讨厌他
Really? He's very good-Iooking.
真的 可德弗林很漂亮
Alex...
亚历克斯,
I've told you before, Mr. Devlin doesn't mean a thing to me.
我跟你说过 我对他并没一点意思
I'd like to be convinced.
我愿意相信
Would you maybe care to convince me, Alicia...
如果你愿意让我相信...
that Mr. Devlin means nothing to you?
艾丽茜娅, 你对德弗林一点意思也没有?
...pleased to hear, Sr. Barbosa, that our little theatrical plan is working.
巴伯沙先生, 很庆幸 我们的计划安排得很顺利
We've got hold of something concrete for a change.
到底掌握了一点情况
I'm delighted, gentlemen. What is it?
那太好了, 什么情况
Professor Otto Rensler is working here in Brazil.
威利亚奥托兰教授正在巴西进行研究
One of Germany's scientific wizards.
一个天才的德国科学家登场
I didn't know he was here.
我不知道此人在这里
He's living and experimenting in Sebastian's house.
他现在在塞巴斯蒂安家进行研究工作
They call him Doctor Anderson.
现在都叫他安德森博土
Entre!
进来
Excuse me, sir.
对不起
Miss Huberman wishes to see Captain Prescott or Mr. Devlin.
休伯曼小姐想见上校 或者德弗林先生
- Do you mean she's here? - Yes, sir.
- 她来了? - 是
- Well, show her in, Hubero. - Yes, sir.
- 叫她进来 - 是
I don't like this. I don't like her coming here.
这不好, 我不愿意她上这儿来
She's had me worried for some time. A woman of that sort.
她叫我不放心, 像她那样的女人
What sort is that, Mr. Beardsley?
哪样的女人, 先生?
I don't think any of us have any illusions about her character.
我想我们对她的品行不抱幻想对吗?
Not at all. Not in the slightest.
一点不抱幻想
Miss Huberman is first, last and always not a lady.
休伯曼小姐当然不是一个高贵的女人
She may be risking her life...
她可以冒生命危险
but when it comes to being a lady...
可一说到高贵
she doesn't hold a candle to your wife, sir...
她当然比不到你妻子...
sitting in Washington...
可以坐在华盛顿
playing bridge with three other ladies of great honour and virtue.
跟那班高贵的女人打桥牌
- Take it easy, Dev. - Sorry.
- 好了, 德弗林先生 - 对不起
I think those remarks about my wife are uncalled for.
你对我妻子的评语完全没必要
Withdrawn. Apologise, sir.
我收回, 向你道歉
- How do you do, Miss Huberman? - How do you do?
- 你好, 休伯曼小姐 - 你好
- This is Mr. Beardsley and Sr. Julio Barbosa. Sit down? - thake you
- 这是比斯利先生和巴伯沙先生 请坐 - 谢谢
You have the esteem of my government
我们巴西政府向你表示敬意, 小姐
But we are worried about your visiting this office.
你的来访使我们感到不安
I promise not to break the rules again...
我一定不再违反规定
but I need some advice and I couldn't find Mr. Devlin.
我要请示, 可是找不到德弗林先生
In fact, I need it before lunch.
本来我午饭前就要来的
Well, has something happened?
出什么事了?
Yes, something rather confusing.
有件事...叫我很为难
Mr. Sebastian has asked me to marry him.
塞巴斯蒂安先生, 他要跟我结婚
- What? - Well, well.
- 是这样? -对, 是这样
He wants me to marry him right away. I 'm to give him my answer at lunch.
他要马上跟我结婚 要我在午饭前给他回复
I don't know what the department might think about such a step?
可是我不知道上级对这件事怎么看
Are you willing to go this far for us?
你愿意为我们迈出这一步吗?休伯曼小姐
Yes, if you wish.
就看你们需要了
What do you think of this, Devlin?
你怎么看? 德弗林
I think it's a useful idea.
我看这主意还不错
You know the situation better than any of us.
情况比我们大家都了解
May I ask what inspired Alex Sebastian to go this far?
请问是什么事情使你迈出这一步呢?
He's in love with me.
他爱上了我
And he thinks you're in love with him?
你有没有爱上他?
Yes, that's what he thinks.
他以为我爱他
Gentlemen, it's the cream of the chest.
诸位, 这真是良机难得呀
Then, it's all right?
那么...可以...
Well, yes, I'd say so.
我看可以
Of course, it's a perfect marriage for us.
当然, 对我们来说, 这是个理想的婚姻
There's only one thing: won't it delay us a bit?
只是有一点, 就会耽误了
What do you mean?
什么意思?
Mr. Sebastian is a very romantic fellow.
塞巴斯蒂安是个风流的家伙
Isn't he, Alicia?
是吗? 艾丽茜娅
Yes.
是的
Then, he'll probably want to take his bride away for a long honeymoon.
他会带新娘子出去渡一个很长的蜜月
- Won't that hold us up? - Devlin's got a point here.
- 这不耽误了? - 没想到这一层
I don't know, I think we can rely on Miss Huberman...
这也难说 我看休伯曼小姐
to get back into the house quickly.
会拿主意赶快回来的
Yes, I think I can manage that.
我看这个我能做到
Well, everything seems to be nicely arranged.
既然这一切安排妥当了
I don't think you need me here anymore, do you, Captain Prescott?
我看这儿用不着我了, 对吗? 上校
I do want to thank you,  Miss Huberman very much.
休伯曼小姐, 我要感谢你, 非常感谢你
So far everything has been managed with great intelligence.
我认为这一切, 都是经过精心安排的
Yes, thank you very much.
非常感谢你
Are you sure she didn't come down here to see you?
你肯定她来这里来不是为了找你这个...
To capture the rich Alexander Sebastian for a husband?
...有钱的亚历克塞巴斯蒂安做丈夫?
Don't be absurd. She didn't even know I was here.
别瞎想, 她根本不知道我在这儿
Well, we'll discuss it more fully tonight.
今天晚上我们得好好的谈谈
We'll not discuss it tonight.
今天晚上我们不谈了
All these carping questions are the expression of your jealousy.
所有这些这些问题都出自你的妒忌
You've always been jealous of any woman I've ever shown any interest in.
就是你妒忌我过去中意的那些女人一样
In this case, there is nothing more to discuss.
所以这件事没什么好谈的了
You mean you're going ahead with this marriage?
那么你的意思就是要结婚了?
I mean that the wedding will be next week.
我的意思, 下星期就结婚
It will be private.
不请外人
We shall both be pleased to have you present, if you wish.
如果你愿意光临, 我无限荣幸!
- Good evening, sir. - Good evening.
- 晚上好, 先生 - 晚上好
- Madam! - Good evening, Joseph.
- 太太!  - 晚上好, 约瑟夫
It doesn't look very cheerful here.
哇, 这好像冷冰冰的
I'm sorry, Madame Sebastian wasn't certain you would be back tonight.
老太太认定了你今天晚上不会回来
Why not? I telegraphed her.
为什么? 我打过电报
Madame Sebastian said we were all to retire, sir.
是老太太吩咐我们休息的
Where is my mother?
老太太呢?
Madame Sebastian went to bed very early, sir.
老太太很早就睡觉了
I'm sorry, dear, I'm afraid this isn't a very bright homecoming.
对不起, 亲爱的, 没想到约你回家会这么冷清
- That's all right, Alex. - What shall we do?
- 没关系, 亲爱的 -我们做什么?
Shall we have Joseph arrange a little food for us?
是不是叫约瑟夫给我们准备点吃的
Not unless you want to. I'm rather tired myself.
你想吃我陪你, 不过我有点累
We'll go right up, then.
那我们上去吧
- Goodnight, Joseph. - Goodnight, Madam.
- 明天见 - 明天见
I'd like to have all my dresses put out on the beds here.
把我所有的衣服都放在床上
Don't hang anything up. I like to know where everything goes.
一件也别挂, 我喜欢自己收拾
Joseph, would you've the closets aired?
约瑟夫, 有壁橱吗?
Yes, Madame.
有, 夫人
Oh, this isn't very large. I'll need more room.
哦, 这壁橱不够大, 不够放
- This door is locked. - That's used for a storeroom, Madame.
- 这边锁着呢? - 当储藏室用的, 夫人
- Oh, may I have the key? - I do not have the keys, Madame.
- 把钥匙给我 - 我没有钥匙, 夫人
Where are they?
钥匙呢?
Madame Sebastian has charge of all the house keys.
所有的钥匙都由老太太管, 夫人
Do you know where Mr. Sebastian is?
塞巴斯蒂安先生在哪?
I think he's having a business meeting in the study, Madame.
他大概在楼下跟股东们一起谈生意
I miss Hupka. He was a first-class metallurgist.
伊米尔·虎泊克可惜呀 第一流的冶金专家
Klieten is just as good.
格拉金也不错
Such is your opinion.
这是你的看法
- But I don't want to criticise. - What were you asking?
- 我不想多加批评 - 那你想要什么?
Oh, you want a report, a written report.
你要做个报告 书面报告!
Well, my friends, my work is done.
对了, 朋友们 工作还是顺利的嘛
You've been successful?
你们成功了
Yes.
是的
- Oh, I'm very sorry. - Oh, no, come on in.
- 噢, 实在对不起, 我... - 进来吧
I'm sorry to interrupt you. I didn't know you were busy.
不, 打扰你们了, 你们正忙着
Some of the closets are locked. Could you give me the keys?
壁橱锁着呢? 打开给我好吗?
I'm sorry. I'd forgotten about the keys.
噢, 对不起! 这事我忘了
Of course, I'll get them for you at once.
我立刻给你拿钥匙
I'll bring the keys to you right away, my dear.
我马上把钥匙交给你, 亲爱的
Mother, Mother!
妈妈, 妈妈
Well, there they are.
好的, 都在这儿
I'm afraid I'm going to be busy for the rest of the morning.
我上午恐怕很忙, 亲爱的
- See you at lunch. - Thank you, dear.
- 午饭时见 - 谢谢
Mr. Sebastian has the keys for this, Madame.
这把钥匙是归塞巴斯蒂安先生管的
It's the wine cellar.
这是酒窖
Then, the wince cellar's the obvious place to look.
为什么不去? 酒窖你应该去看看
- Alex has the key to that. - Then get it from him.
- 钥匙在亚历克斯那里 - 去跟他要
Get it. Yes, how?
要? 怎么要?
Don't you leave near him?
你们还分彼此?
What do I look for if I get the key?
拿到了钥匙我该做什么?
You look for a bottle of wine,  like the one that rattled that fellow.
有没有把哪个家伙惹急了的那种酒
All the bottles look alike to me. I'm no mastermind.
就凭这些酒瓶, 我看都一样 我没那本事
You're doing all right.
你干的不错
It's no fun, Dev.
真不好受的
Too late for that now, isn't it?
后悔来不及了
Look, why don't you persuade your husband to throw a large shindig...
我说, 为什么不叫你丈夫来个大请客?
so he can introduce his bride to Rio society say sometime next week?
让你跟这个社交界见见面 就在下星期行吗?
Why?
为什么?
Consider me invited.
当然也得请我
I'll try to find out about that wine cellar business.
那酒窖的玩意儿叫我去看看
I don't think my husband is interested in entertaining just yet.
我看我的丈夫现在还没这份心思请客
The honeymoon isn't over, eh?
还陶醉在蜜月里, 是吗?
Don't underestimate your charms, Mrs. Sebastian, you can handle it.
别小看你的魅力, 塞巴斯蒂安夫人 你能办到
It's not going to be so easy about you. He thinks you're in love with me.
请你来恐怕不好吧 他认为你爱我
Tell him if you invited me to the house and saw how happily married you were...
跟他说, 请我到你们家来 让我看看你们的婚姻是多么美满
the horrid passion I have for you might be torn out of me.
这样我对你的狂热就从此打消
That sounds very logical.
真是合情合理
Good, next week then. And get the key.
好呀, 下星期把钥匙弄到手
I have to fly up to Bel Air. But I'll be back in time.
我就要去柏林 会赶回来的
All right, I'll be looking forward to seeing you.
好吧 我就等着再见吧
It's always a pleasure meeting you, Madame.
跟你见面欢快之至, 夫人
I'm surprised Mr. Devlin coming tonight.
德弗林先生今天你来我感到很意外
I don't blame anyone for being in love with you, darling.
有人爱上你并不奇怪, 亲爱的
I just hope that nothing will happen to give him any false impression.
我只希望邀请他不会发生误会
I'll be with you in a minute.
我一会儿就出来
Darling.
亲爱的
It's not that I don't trust you, but when you're in love at my age...
不是我不信任你, 到我这岁数
every man that looks at your woman is a menace.
有人看你一眼, 就我都是威胁
Will you forgive me for even talking aboutit?
噢, 我这么说说都觉得对不起你
I'm very contrite.
我太多心了
I think we might join the rest of the party now.
我想我们现在可以进去了
I think all our guests are here.
客人大概到齐了
Where can I find Madame Sebastian?
我来晚了, 塞巴斯蒂安夫人呢?
- Try the door, sir. - Thanks.
- 在大厅 - 谢谢
- Hello, Dev. - Good evening.
- 你好, 德弗林 - 你好!
- You haven't seen the house? - No, it's quite a jolly little cottage.
- 你头一次来我家吧? - 你们这房子真不错
- Let me show you around the place. - Later. His nibs is on the trail.
- 我领你到处看看 - 他在盯着我
- Devlin, glad to see you. - Good night.
- 你好 - 你好!
It was kind of your bride to invite me.
欢迎 谢谢你记得邀请了我
We both invite you, Mr. Devlin.
是我们两个人邀请你的, 德弗林先生
Will you see our guest is fed, my dear? And amused...
亲爱的, 你好好招呼一下客人, 我说
Oh, excuse me.
噢, 对不起
Madame Esterich, I'm so glad to see you.
塞巴斯蒂安夫人, 我真高兴
- It's not going to be easy. - Why?
- 看来不太好下手啊 - 怎么?
He's quite sensitive about you. He's going to watch us like a hawk.
他很注意! 像头鹰一样盯着我们
Yes, he's rather jealous of anyone.
不, 他这人很妒忌
Where did you get the key? Off his chain?
从他钥匙链里拿的钥匙?
Yes.
是的
Let's hope the liquor doesn't run out and start him down the cellar for more.
但愿酒够吃的 要不然, 塞巴斯蒂安要去酒窖拿酒
- I hadn't thought about that. - Quite a point.
- 这我没想到 - 这很重要
Thank you.
谢谢
Mr. Devlin, how nice! You remember me?
德弗林先生, 还记得我吗?
Senora Ortiz.
爱尔迪夫人!
How sweet, young men usually have short memories.
真你还记得, 年轻人总是记性差的
Here's something I adore: champagne.
我就是爱喝香槟酒
Oh, may I?
唉, 对不起!
- Joseph? - Madame?
- 约瑟夫 - 夫人
Do you think you have enough champagne for the rest of the evening?
你看今晚这些香槟酒够不够喝呢?
I don't know, Madame. I hope so.
很难说, 夫人, 应该能够
- Enjoying yourself, Mr. Devlin? - Very much, thank you.
- 还愉快吗?德弗林先生 - 很愉快, 谢谢!
There are so many things I'd like to ask about the States.
我想跟你打听美国的消息
I haven't heard anything for a long time.
我好久没听到那边的情况了
I'll be glad to tell you. Will you excuse me, Senora Ortiz?
只要我知道的 请原谅, 夫人!
I don't mind, certainly!
没关系
- We'd better hurry. - Lots of time.
- 得快点了 - 不急
No, Joseph might have to ask Alex for more wine.
不, 约瑟夫说要跟亚历克斯拿酒
He's running out faster than he thought.
酒恐怕喝得差不多了
I'm sorry to hear that.
这就很糟糕了
- Is he watching? - Yes.
- 他在盯着我们? - 是的
You'd better go out into the garden and wait around the back of the house.
你先到花园里去, 到屋的后面等我
I'll show you the wine cellar door.
我领你到酒窖去
- Nice party, isn't it? - It's a wonderful party.
- 宴会你满意吗 - 非常满意
I think you've done it wonderfully well.
你今晚的表现太好了
I'm very proud. Mr. Devlin bothering you much?
我很得意 德弗林先生麻烦你了?
No, darling. He's trying to drown his sorrows.
不, 亲爱的, 他借酒消愁呢
Excuse me, think I'll ask the orchestra to play some Brazilian music.
对不起, 我去叫乐队奏一点巴西乐曲
They've played waltzes all evening.
他们一直在奏华尔兹舞曲
All right, dear.
好吧
- That's the door. - Right.
- 快进来 - 好的
I'll keep the garden door open and I'll tell you if anything happens.
我把去花园的门开着, 有情况我告诉你
What's happened?
怎么啦?
Look, Vintage sand.
陈酒是沙子?
We've got to leave things as we found them.
得把东西按原样搁好
Help me find a bottle of wine with the same label as these others.
找一个同样牌子的酒瓶来
- It isn't really sand, is it? - I think it's some kind of metal ore.
- 但这不像是沙子, 对吗? - 大概是一种矿物
- This is a bit weird. - I'm terrified.
- 这里头有鬼 - 我怕极了
Just pretend you're a janitor. Janitors are never terrified.
就当你是狩猎吧 狩猎时不会害怕的
I have a feeling we're very slow.
真觉得我们太慢了
We're on schedule. Take it easy.
我们在按计划来, 放轻松点儿
I can hear someone coming.
好像有人来了
Oh, that'll be nice.
哦, 没关系
Think if he comes down with Joseph.
他跟约瑟夫一块来了
Unfortunate.
真倒霉! 走吧
Someone is coming.
有人来了
It's Alex. He's seen us.
亚历克斯来了
Wait a minute. I'm going to kiss you.
等等 那我只有亲你
- No, he'll only think... - That's what I want him to think.
- 不!他会以为我们 - 就是要让他这样想
You better stay upstairs,  they may need you.
你上楼去, 恐怕上面忙不过来
Yes, sir.
好的, 先生
Oh, Dev, Dev!
德弗林
Push me away!
把我推开
I'm sorry to intrude on this tender scene.
对不起, 打扰你们的雅兴了
I couldn't help what happened: he's been drinking.
一点也没有办法, 他喝多了
So, he carried you down here.
哦!就抱着你到这儿了?
Please, Alex!
别这样, 亚历克斯!
- You love him. - No, of course not. Please go.
- 你爱他? - 我不爱他, 你走吧
For what it's worth, as an apology,  your wife is telling the truth.
你妻子说的真话胜过我对你的道歉
I knew her before you,  I loved here before you...
我比你先认识她, 先爱上她
but I wasn't as lucky as you.
你比我运气好
Sorry, Alicia.
对不起, 艾丽茜娅
- Please, go. - Goodnight.
- 你走吧 - 再见
Alex, don't be foolish. I came down here...
亚历克斯, 别瞎想了, 我...
because he threatened to make a scene unless I'd see him alone.
我来这是因为我要不单独跟他见面 他就会吵起来
He kissed you.
他吻你了
I couldn't stop him.
我拗不过他, 我想...
We'll talk about it later. Your guests are upstairs.
我们回头再谈吧 客人在楼上
Will you please go to them?
请去照应一下
Mr. Devlin, are you going so soon?
德弗林先生, 你这就要走了?
Yes, I'm afraid I have to be up early in the morning.
是的, 我明天早上还得起早呢
Thank you and goodnight.
再见
- Joseph? - Yes, sir.
- 约瑟夫 - 是的
- We can go down for the wine now. - Yes, sir.
- 现在下去拿酒吧 - 是的
Joseph, I don't think we need to give them any more champagne.
我说约瑟夫... 我看用不着拿那么多的香槟了
- We still have some upstairs. - Yes, sir.
- 楼上不是还有一点吗? - 是的
- There's whisky and the wine. - Yes, sir.
- 可是还有威士忌和红酒吗? - 有的
Well, I think we'll give them that.
就拿这个招待吧
I'm sorry about what happened, Alex.
刚才的事真对不起你!
My dear, I shall never forgive myself for behaving like a schoolboy.
噢, 亲爱的, 我永远不能原谅 我刚才那种幼稚的行动
- Then you believe me? - Of course.
- 你相信我了? - 当然
- It isn't worth mentioning again. - Thank you.
- 那件事不要再提了 - 谢谢
- Are you coming up? - Not for a little while.
- 你不上楼? - 等等再说
Dr. Anderson's waiting for me in the study.
安德森博士在书房里等我
Sleep well.
先去睡吧
It was a very successful party.
宴会办得还不错
- Goodnight, then. - Goodnight.
- 回头见 - 晚安
Thanks for being so nice.
你待我太好了
Mother!
妈妈
Why are you up so early?
你这么早就起来了
I need your help.
你帮帮我!
Something is wrong?
出什么事了?
A great deal, Alicia.
出大事了, 艾丽茜娅
I have expected it.
我早就预料到了
I knew, I knew!
料到了
What is it? Mr. Devlin?
什么事? 那个德弗林?
No.
不!
I'm married to an American agent.
我娶了个美国特工人员了
Yes, it's easy to see now.
对, 现在事情都清楚了
I knew but I didn't see.
怎么当时没看出来呢
They picked her because of her father.
是靠她父亲关系派她来的
I must have been insane, mad. Behaved like an idiot.
我一定是疯了
To believe in her with her clinging kisses!
她的温柔体贴让我像傻子一样相信她
Stop wallowing in your foul memories.
别想你的良辰美景了
Well, what do I do?
那我怎么办哪?
There's nothing to do. I'm done, finished.
一点办法都没有, 完了!
- They'll find out. - They won't find out.
- 他们会发现的 - 他们发现不了的
They'll find out what I'm married to.
他们会发现他的
Look what they did to Emil Hupka. Emil, who did nothing.
看他们怎么干掉伊米尔的 伊米尔没做什么
And I betrayed them. I bungled and there's no excuse.
我背叛了他们, 捅了漏子, 罪有应得
I'd do the same myself: kill the fool that betrayed them.
要是有人背叛了我 我一定把他杀了
- There's no need for them to find out. - Mathis is very sharp.
- 不让他们发现就是了 - 马西斯这人很精
He dislikes you, but his criticism of your talents wouldn't
而且不喜欢你 对你才能的评价还不至于想到
go that far to image that you're married to an American agent.
你会娶个美国特工女人
We are protected by the enormity of you stupidity for a time.
因为你们暂时还不会被人发觉
- Listen, I'll take care of her myself. - No, not in that way.
- 艾丽茜娅我要亲自对付她 - 不, 不能那样
I stood looking at her while she was asleep and I could have...
站在她床边看她睡觉 我真想...
Quiet, Alex!
冷静点, 亚历克斯
You're almost as impetuous I as before your wedding.
你就像你要结婚的时候那么任性
You barred me from that episode. Let me arrange this one.
你根本不听我的话 这次让我来安排好了
Listen to me. No-one must know what she is.
你听我说 不让一个人知道她是谁
There must be no suspicion of her, of you, of me.
不能让任何人怀疑她、你还有我
She must be allowed to move about freely.
要让她自由行动
But she will be on a leash.
可是要暗地监视
She will learn nothing further to inform.
不能让她得到任何东西去报告
She must go,  but it must happen slowly.
你一定要干掉她 可是这得慢慢来
If she could become ill, and remain ill for a time, until...
她可以生个病嘛 病那么一段时候, 直到...
Drink you coffee, darling,  it's getting cold.
把它给喝了, 亲爱的, 快点
Are you going out this afternoon,  Alex?
今天上午你出去吗? 亚历克斯
No, my dear, I've some letters to write. What are you going to do?
不, 亲爱的, 我要写几封信 你想干什么?
Oh, I just have a little shopping.
出去买点东西
I'd like to go to the imperial. Maybe I'll go to Cosmo's...
到百货公司去看看
and see if they've any new books in from New York.
或者到书店看看有什么纽约的新书
If you're going down there,  will you go into Sisacruz for me...
去那儿是不是顺便看看
and see if my cigars have arrived?
我订的雪茄烟到了没有
Should be about a thousand.
大约一千支左右
If they've, ask them to keep them in the humidor for me.
要是到了, 请他们替我保存好
Anything wrong?
不舒服吗?
No, the light bothers me.
不, 我有点怕光
I have a bit of a headache, would you mind...
好像觉得有点头痛 可以吗?
- yes, I think we can fix that. - Thank you.
- 当然, 我把它放下来 - 谢谢
Some people get too much sun down here, you must be careful.
有的人在这儿太阳晒得太厉害了, 得留点神
I think you can be very proud of yourself.
你一定会感到很自豪吧, 塞巴斯蒂安夫人
That sand that Devlin brought in shows uranium ore.
德弗林送来的矿沙是铀矿沙
So now we know what we're driving at.
我们现在有了头绪了
Your job from now on will be to help us find out where that sand comes from.
你今后的任务是 设法弄清这矿沙是从哪来的
The location of the uranium deposit is of vast importance and...
铀矿的所有地点关系极为重大
we're putting quite a few people on it.
我们已经派很多人去查了
But I think you'll be of great help.
我觉得你...也要出把力
All right.
哦
But that isn't the main reason why I asked you to come up here.
可今天请你来主要不是为了这个
- No? - No, I wanted to tell you...
- 不是这个?  - 我是想告诉你
that I'm going to change your contact in about a week.
不出一星期, 你的联系人要换了
Mr. Devlin's been transferred to Spain.
德弗林先生要调到西班牙去
To Spain?
调西班牙?
- Does Mr. Devlin know that? - Oh yes, he asked for the transfer.
- 他自己知道吗? - 知道, 他自己要求调的
Why?
为什么?
I guess he thought he was going to stale here.
或许他以为在这儿太无聊了
Oh, he wants to leave Rio.
他想离开这儿?
He thought he'd find Spain more interesting.
或许他觉得... 西班牙更有意义
Yes, I imagine it would be. There really isn't very much...
是呀, 我看也是这样
for a brainy fellow like Mr. Devlin to do in Rio any more.
对德弗林先生这样聪明的人来说 这儿实在没可能有可乘之机
Well, of course, it is more or less routine now.
对了, 这儿现在没什么要紧事了
In the meantime I'm to report to Mr. Devlin as usual.
那么, 眼前, 我还是向德弗林先生报告吗?
Yes, he'll be here until the new man arrives.
对, 新任没到之前他还在这儿
Thank you, Captain Prescott,  I'll keep my ears wide open.
谢谢, 布莱斯特上校, 我会留心观察的
- Good bye. - Good bye.
- 再见 - 再见
Oh, and... go easy on that sun, eh?
太阳别晒太多了
Darling, what is it?
亲爱的, 怎么了?
I don't know.
不知道
- Are you in pain? - Yes, I'm so dizzy.
- 不舒服? - 我...我头晕
What happened to her?
她怎么了?
We were walking and she was stricken suddenly.
我们在散步她突然不舒服
I'll be all right. Let's go inside.
我没事, 进屋去吧
I'm sorry I couldn't make it on time.
对不起, 我来晚了
Well, it gets a bit Ionely squatting on a bench all day.
整天坐在长凳上, 真有点冷清
Yes, Rio can be a very dull town.
是呀, 这本来是无聊的事
What's new?
有新情况吗?
Nothing. What's new of you?
没有 你有新情况吗?
Nothing.
没有
Any domestic troubles about the other night?
那天我走了以后, 你们吵了没有?
No.
没有
Any footprints in that sand yet?
矿沙的事有线索吗?
No, nothing yet.
没有, 还没有
Just a social visit, huh?
今天就为打个照面
A little fresh air helps.
换换空气也好
You don't look so hot.
你气色不太好啊
- Well - Sick?
- 是吗? - 病了?
No. Hangover.
不, 喝醉了
That's news. Back to the bottle again, huh?
真是新闻, 又喝起来了
Sort of lightens my chores.
可不, 借酒消愁嘛
- Big party? - Just the family circle.
- 大请客呀 - 家里人聚聚
Sounds quite jolly.
不错啊
it helps life in a dull town.
只不过太无聊了
You ought to take it easy on that liquor.
你这样使劲喝可不行啊
Don't you find Rio a little hard to take, too?
你不是觉得这... 太没劲了吗?
Not a bad town.
这儿挺好的
You look all mashed up: must have been quite an evening.
瞧你困的 晚上一定过得挺美
Yes, it was.
是的, 挺美
Well, if you want to play it that way, go on have fun.
好吧, 你愿意这么过就这么过吧
No reason why you shouldn't.
谁也拦不住你
That's right, Dev. Here's something that belongs to you.
说得对, 德弗林 这一样东西是你的
I should have given it to you sooner.
我早该还给你了
- What is it? - The scarf you lent me once in Miami.
- 什么? - 你在迈阿密借给我的围巾
Cleaning house, huh?
清洁时发现的?
Yeah...
是啊...
Well, goodbye, Dev.
噢, 再见, 德弗林
What do you mean, goodbye?
你什么意思, 再见?
Nothing, just goodbye.
再见就是再见
Fresh air isn't as good for a hangover as I thought.
新鲜空气并不像我想像的那样新鲜
Sit down, you're still tight.
坐下, 你酒还没醒呢
I don't want to.
我不想坐了
Where are you going?
你上哪儿?
Back home.
回家去!
You're not taking care of yourself, Alicia.
你太不注意身体了, 艾丽茜娅
Oh, I feel much better.
我好多了
You look like something awful.
你的气色可太不好了
Circles under the eyes...
你眼圈都黑了
My dear child, you must have a doctor find out...
孩子, 你应该找个医生看看
what is the matter with you.
到底是什么病
I never go near doctors.
我从来没找医生
They always want to cart you off to a hospital.
他们老是想把我送到医院去
Maybe you belong in a hospital.
也许... 你是该到医院去
Tell me when did you first feel sick?
告诉我, 你是什么时候得病的?
I don't remember,  maybe the party, I think.
我...我不记得 可当初那次...请客...
I still think a sea trip...
我看你还是到海上旅行一次
would be much better for you darling nor doctors or hospitals.
比什么医生, 医院要好
A little cruise somewhere. Maybe Spain?
去旅行一下 去一趟西班牙?
Put the roses back in your cheeks, my sweet.
健康就会恢复了
I don't think so. I don't care much for boats.
我看不见得, 我不喜欢坐船
We could go together, my dear.
我陪你去, 亲爱的
If you could bear to leave Alex behind for a few weeks.
如果你舍得离开亚历克斯一个星期
I think I prefer Alex to a case of seasickness.
我真要晕船, 我希望亚历克斯陪着我
I always get seasick.
我一坐船就会晕
Then you might like the mountains.
要么你去爬爬山
The air's fresh and pure and...
山上的空气新鲜
- I'm gong next week. - Oh, you're leaving?
- 我过几天走 - 噢, 你要走了
I'm sorry, I'll miss you.
我会想念你
Yes, I'm delaying my work too long.
我的工作已经耽误了很久啦
If you'll come with me, the mountains won't make you seasick.
你跟我去吧, 爬山是不会晕的
And the Aimress mountains are beautiful, covered with flowers...
艾尔瑞新群山真美呀 到处都是鲜花
What Alicia needs is rest,  not mountain climbing.
艾丽茜娅需要休息 不需要爬山
I've heard about the Aimress.
艾尔瑞斯山我听说过
Did you? Really?
真的, 听说过?
Yes, about the beautiful little native towns.
是呀 还有那些美丽的乡镇
Are you going to Leopoldina?
你是不是去利奥波迪纳?
- No, no, I'm going to Santa Ma... - Care for some more brandy, Otto?
- 不, 我是到圣马... - 喝点白兰地?
No, thanks.
不, 谢谢
I never drink more than one brandy and even this is sometimes too much.
我一杯就够, 要说一杯也喝不了
I'll just finish my coffee.
我喝完这杯咖啡吧 安德森博士!
- No, that is not your... - That's Alicia's...
- 那杯不是你的 - 那是艾丽...
I'm sorry,
对不起!
Yeah, perhaps Alex is right, my dear child.
也许亚历克斯是对的, 孩子!
When you are young, rest is the best doctor.
你还年轻 休息是最好的治疗
if you lie still for a few days...
你要是好好的睡几天
reading, relaxing, forgetting all your troubles...
看看书, 休息休息, 什么也别想
it might be as well as a medicinal ocean air.
这可比什么药跟治疗都好
And when I come back you will be all well...
等我回来, 你一定好了
making us all very happy once more.
我们大家又会高高兴兴的了
Excuse me, I want to go to bed, I feel...
对不起, 我... 我要睡觉, 我觉得...
Pain again, darling?
哪儿不舒服?
Sorry to complain again.
对不起
Shall I take you up to your room?
我送你回房间休息
May I help you, my dear? Some hot water, maybe?
要我帮忙吗? 也许要点热水, 对吗?
No, no, please don't bother.
不...
I'll be all right.
我没事
If she's no better in the morning, I insist you call a doctor.
要是她早上还这样, 我帮你叫医生来
I don't like the way she looks.
我看她神色不对, 亚历克斯
I'm worried about her.
我很担心她 我怕她病得太厉害
Alicia! Joseph!
艾丽茜娅, 怎么了?
Joseph! Help me with her, will you?
约瑟夫, 帮帮忙 怎么了? 快帮他送上去
- You must take her up to bed. - Yes, up to her room.
- 把她送到屋里 - 对
Come on, my dear.
走吧, 亲爱的
I told you she was sick.
瞧, 我说她是病了
Now, come on, don't excite yourself. Be quiet.
别太紧张了 醒醒
No, no, go away! No! No!
不...走开 不, 不!
The attack's come so suddenly! I'm sure is not serious.
她歇会儿就好了
We must get a doctor. The poor child is suffering so much.
我看得找个医生来 这孩子病得不轻呀
I'll call the hospital. I'll get Doctor Lisard.
我打个电话给医生 我自己跟医生说
Don't worry, dear Otto. We'll get a doctor, a good one.
别麻烦了 我们会找医生, 找个好医生
We'll take the best care of her.
好好的照料她
Joseph, disconnect the telephone.
约瑟夫, 把电话拆了
Madame must have absolute quiet.
夫人需要绝对的安静
Take it out of the room, Joseph.
把电话拿走
Five days, eh?
五天, 是吧?
Say, that must be quite a binge she's on.
昨天, 她这次真的往死里喝
I don't think so.
我不这么想
You said she was drinking last week,  drunk when you saw her.
你说上星期她喝醉了 你亲眼看见了? 是呀
- But I've had time to think it over. - Think what over.
- 后来我又想了想 - 怎么了?
That drinking of hers. I don't believe it.
她说她喝醉了, 可我不信
Why should she lie to you about that?
她干嘛要对你撒谎?
I don't know.
不知道
But she wasn't drunk, she was sick.
她不是喝醉了 她像是病了
Maybe that's why she hasn't shown up.
或许这就是她为什么没有现身
She looked like the ragged end of nowhere.
她好像有点精神萎靡
- It still sounds like a hangover to me. - Well, I'm going to pay her a call.
- 这么说我还是觉得她喝醉了 - 我去找她一次
Wait a minute! I don't want you to mess things up.
别把事搅挥了
We hope to close this case down in a few days.
没几天这案子就可以破了
I won't mess anything up.
我不会搅挥的
Just a social call. I'm a friend of the family.
上门去看看 我是他们家的老朋友了
All right, go ahead if you want to. But don't take any chances.
你要去就去吧 可是, 你别大意
And call me up when you get back!
还有, 回来给我打个电话
I'll do that!
我会打的
Good evening, sir.
晚上好, 先生
Good evening. Family home tonight?
晚上好 都在家吗?
Yes, sir.
都在
Would you mind telling Mr. Sebastian that Mr. Devlin is here?
请你告诉塞巴斯蒂安先生 就说我来了
- What is it, Joseph? - I'm sorry, sir, but...
- 怎么了? 约瑟夫 - 先生, 因为...
since Mr. Sebastian asked me not to disturb him...
塞巴斯蒂安先生说过 不要去打搅他, 我看这...
Asleep?
睡了?
No sir, he's in the study with some business associates.
不是的, 他和几个股东在书房里商量事
- How long will he be tied up? - I don't know, sir.
- 多久才散? - 这我不知道
- Is Mrs. Sebastian home? - Yes, sir.
- 夫人在家吗? - 在家!
- Would you mind telling her? - I'm afraid I can't, sir.
- 请你通知她 - 恐怕今儿不行呀 先生
Why not?
为什么?
Mrs. Sebastian is very ill and confined to her bed.
塞巴斯蒂安夫人病得很厉害 躺在床上
I'm sorry to hear that.
那真不幸
- How long has she been ill? - A week.
- 病了多久了? - 一星期
- Has she had a doctor? - I think so, sir.
- 找过大夫了? - 太太找过
We're all very concerned about her.
我们都替她着急
If you'll wait here, Mr. Devlin, I'll tell Mr. Sebastian.
你不妨等一等, 德弗林先生 我去通知塞巴斯蒂安先生
Right.
好
- Excuse me, sir? - What is it, Joseph?
- 对不起 - 什么事? 约瑟夫
Mr. Devlin to see you, sir.
德弗林先生要见你
Tell him I'll be with him in a minute, will you?
告诉他我一会儿就来
Yes, sir.
好的
Go on, professor. This sounds serious to me.
往下说, 安德森, 我看情况很严重
To me, also.
我看也是
- What happened Monday? - Same thing.
- 星期一怎么样了? - 老样子
When I left the bank a man was following me.
我一出银行就有个人跟着我
This morning when I went to the ticket office...
今天早晨我去买火车票
the same man came inside and stood beside me.
那个人又跟着我, 站在我身边
Alicia!
艾丽茜娅
Dev!
德弗林
Alicia, what's wrong with you?
艾丽茜娅, 你怎么了?
I'm so glad you came.
你来了真好
I had to. I couldn't stand any more.
我得来呀, 我再也忍不住了
Waiting and worrying about you.
再也不能这样惦着你
It wasn't a hangover you had that day.
那天你不是喝醉了
You were sick then. What is it?
你是病了, 什么病?
Yes, I was sick then.
你到底来了
What's wrong with you, Alicia?
什么病?
- Oh, Dev. - What is it dear? What's wrong?
- 德弗林 - 哪儿不舒服?
They're poisoning me. I couldn't get away from them.
他们下毒药了 他们不让我走
I tried, but it was too weak.
我想走, 可是没力气
How long?
有多久了?
Since the party.
从那次请客以后
Alex and his mother found out.
亚历克斯和他的母亲发现了
You want to try to sit up.
来, 坐起来
Sit up. I've got to get you out of here.
坐起来 我要把你带走
I thought you had gone.
我以为你走了
No, I had to see you once to speak my piece.
不, 我至少还得见你一次
I was getting out because I love you.
我要调走是因为我爱你
I couldn't bear seeing you and him together.
你跟他在一起我不能忍受
Oh, you love me! Why didn't you tell me before?
亲爱的 你为什么不早说呢?
I know, but I couldn't see straight or think straight.
是呀 都怪我过去晕了头了
I was a fat-headed guy full of pain. It tore me up not having you.
我是那个诉苦无门的大混蛋 没有你, 我的心都撕裂了
Oh, you love me! You love me!
哦, 你爱我! 哦, 你爱我!
Long ago. All the time since the beginning.
认识你那天就爱上你了
Here, put on your robe.
穿上这个
- Come on. - Yes.
- 来吧 - 好
Try to stand up.
你坐好了
Dev, I'm afraid, I can't make it because they gave me pills to sleep.
德弗林, 恐怕我坐不起来了 他们喂我吃了那药就想睡
Keep away. Keep talking.
你醒醒, 你说话呀
- Have you got a coat? - In the closet.
- 大衣呢 - 在壁橱里
They didn't want the others to know about me.
我的事他还瞒着别人
Keep talking.
说呀
Come on. What happened?
后来呢? 说呀! 怎么啦?
- Alex found out. - And the others haven't?
- 亚历克斯发觉了 - 别人没发觉
They'd kill him if they knew. They killed Emil.
发觉了他就没命了 他们杀了伊米尔
Are you in pain?
哪儿不舒服?
I don't know, the pills...
吃了药不觉得
Give me your feet...
站起来
Say it again. It keeps me awake.
你说话呀, 要不我要睡着了
I love you.
我爱你
Stand up! Stand up!
站起来...
Come on, wake up! Talk!
醒醒, 说话呀
- Dr. Anderson... - Go on, go on.
- 安德森... 博士说... - 什么
Walk! Talk!
接着说...
The sand comes from the Aimress mountains.
沙从艾尔瑞斯山脉来的
We'll find it.
他跑不了的
From a town, Santa Ma... something.
那地方叫什么圣马... 什么
Good girl. We'll take care of it later.
你行的 我们会守着他的
- Come on, keep walking! - I'm afraid, Dev.
- 别睡着, 接着走哇 - 不行, 恐怕不行
They're all in the house. We can't make it.
他们都在家 我们走不了
Don't ever leave me.
再也别离开我了
You'll never get rid of me again.
你想甩也甩不掉我了
I'll never try to.
我再也不了
Brace up. Here he comes.
打起精神, 他来了
What are you doing, Alicia? What is this, Mr. Devlin?
你干什么? 怎么回事? 德弗林先生?
I'm taking her to the hospital to get the poison out of her.
我要把她送到医院去 她中毒了
Poison?
中毒?
Would you like your friends downstairs to know?
你要让楼下的朋友们知道吗? 告诉他们吧
I'm taking her back to her room.
我把她送回屋里去
No, I'll raise quite a rumpus if you try.
你试试看, 我可不是好惹的
Alex!
亚历克斯?
- He knows? - Yes.
- 他知道了? - 是的
What is happening, Alex?
怎么回事, 亚历克斯
Alicia!
是艾丽茜娅
- She's worse? - Yes.
- 她病重了? - 是的
All right, dear, we're going.
好了, 亲爱的, 我们走!
You haven't forgotten what they did to Emil, have you Sebastian?
他们怎么对待伊米尔的 你没忘吧, 塞巴斯蒂安先生
Help him, Alex.
帮帮他, 亚历克斯
I'm glad you have a head on you, Madame.
还是你有头脑, 老太太
I'm not afraid to die.
我并不怕死
You've got your chance, here and now.
你想死, 现在就是机会
Tell them who she is.
告诉他们她是谁
Need any help, Alex?
要帮忙吗? 亚历克斯
- No, we can handle her. - Where are you taking her?
- 不用, 我们行 - 送她到哪儿?
You answer that one, Sebastian.
你来回答, 塞巴斯蒂安
To the hospital.
到医院去
Alex, talk to them, quick!
亚历克斯, 你快回答呀
I'm glad she's going.
早该去了
You should not have waited so long, Alex.
已经耽误得太久了
What am I going to do, start shooting?
你要我怎么样? 开枪吗?
Hold on, darling, you've only got about twenty yards to go.
挺住, 亲爱的, 离大门不远啦
What happened, Alex?
怎么啦?
Oh, she collapsed.
她... 晕过去了
Mr. Devlin heard her scream when he was waiting for me.
德弗林先生在等我的时候听到一声叫
Come on, Alicia.
挺住, 阿丽茜娅
Yes, I telephoned the hospital as soon as I saw how she was.
我一见她那样就打电话给医院了
- You have a car, Mr. Devlin? - In front.
- 德弗林先生, 你有车吗? - 在门口
Your hat, Alex.
快走, 亚历克斯
You're going with them, Anna?
你也跟着去?
No, Alex will call me up. I'll wait here.
不, 亚历克斯会给我打电话的
The sooner the doctor sees her...
我在这儿等着
Poor child!
慢点! 可怜的孩子!
- How do you feel? - Bit dizzy.
- 觉得怎么样了? - 头挺晕的
- Take some deep breaths. - Hurry, hurry.
- 做做深呼吸 - 快, 快
- Just a minute, I must sit with her. - No room, Sebastian.
- 等一等, 让我也上车 - 没你坐的地方
- You must take me, they're watching! - That's your headache.
- 把我带上, 他们盯着我呢 - 你自己看着办吧
Please take me! Please, please!
求求你...
There is no telephone in her room to call the hospital.
卧室里没有电话, 怎么可能打到医院里呢?
Alex, will you come in, please? I wish to talk to you.
亚历克斯, 请你进来一下 我想跟你谈谈